[tense music]
[engine revving]
[metal crashes]
[indistinct chatter]
[faint thumping]
[man speaking indistinctly]
[keys jingling]
[clicks]
[man over earpiece]
He's coming down.
[telephone ringing]
[gate opening]
[indistinct chatter]
[elevator bell dings]
Well, I wanted to reassure
you and your father,
you're in good hands.
Ambitious...
- How'd it go?
- Almost done.
[businessman
speaks indistinctly]
All this...
began with that.
We're gonna take great care
of your company, sir.
I know you will.
[businessman
speaks indistinctly]
[car honks]
[businessman]
All right, gentlemen.
See you in a week
when we make it official.
Great day.
[car door opens]
[car door closes]
Congrats.
Thank you, brother.
Relax.
This is what you wanted.
You should be happy.
I am.
Are you?
For me, it's, uh...
bittersweet.
[soft music]
- [Tibu] Thank you.
- [staff speaks Thai]
[Tibu in English] Do what
you need to do, then come over
so we can settle
our business, yeah?
[Cole] Sure.
- [Cole] All good?
- Yeah, all good.
Oh, and, boss, uh,
tomorrow night's guest list
just came through.
It's on your tablet.
[Cole] Thanks. I'll take a look.
[door opens]
How did you become
so good at this?
When I was a rookie,
they had me work the jail.
Best chess players in the world
live behind bars.
Mm.
Do you miss
being a police officer?
I miss the action.
Not the politics.
- [chess piece thuds]
- Check.
[Tibu] You can never go back?
[Cole] No.
I made some mistakes.
Pissed off the wrong people.
[inhales sharply]
Today, um...
would have been
your father's birthday.
[chuckles]
Trying to break
my concentration.
Whatever it takes to win.
Well, you'll need
all the help you can get.
[chuckles]
You're okay?
Yeah.
Thanks for remembering.
Oh. I wish I could have met him.
[Cole] Yeah, you'd have
loved him.
He was, uh...
I mean, he could play.
He'd have kicked your ass
worse than I do.
- [chuckles]
- And taken your money.
Check.
[exhales]
If you were me,
what would you do?
I'd probably surrender.
Ahh.
[Tibu laughing]
- But you don't have to.
- Ah.
No, you've won.
[both chuckle]
[gulps, inhales]
[smacks lips]
[chuckles softly]
[sighs]
[clears throat]
Happy birthday, Dad.
[birds chirping]
[staff speaks Thai]
[Kameron in English] The dinner
precedes cake cutting.
Ready for your big night?
My father's gonna make a speech.
- You know how much I hate this.
- [both chuckle]
[engine starts]
[speaks Thai]
[in English] Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Yes, well, it was like, um,
what is-- what is this language
you've been learning?
I don't-- I don't recognize it.
Are you sure
you've been learning?
[muffled laughter]
[speaking Thai]
[all exclaim]
[speaking Thai indistinctly]
[chattering, laughing]
[tapping glass]
[in English] I have.
I have, yeah. I went last year.
[Tibu clears throat]
[breathes deeply]
You spend your life
chasing success,
only to one day realize
that all that matters
is how you achieved it.
What you've left behind.
- Ours is a very dirty business.
- Who's that?
[Tibu] But our company's
"ethics over profits" spirit...
[Taran] Jaran Daniles.
Trans-Pacific Exports.
Cleanest record on the high seas
over the past 40 years,
and that... is what
I am most proud of.
- [guest 1] Yes.
- [guests clapping]
[guest 2] Bravo.
[Tibu] I'd like to thank you
for joining me...
- [man] Yes. Good to meet you.
- ...and my son Kameron
on this special occasion.
[man] El Salvador.
[Tibu] Tonight, we celebrate
a new chapter
for the Campallo family.
A new beginning.
I'm so proud
of the work Kameron did
to grow the business,
to help make this sale
a reality.
Without his efforts,
none of this
would have been possible.
And we did it the right way.
Together.
Come.
[guests clapping and cheering]
[guests cheering loudly]
Now, we toast and drink.
[cheering continues]
[Tibu] To celebrate this day.
The one you wanted.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- [guests clapping]
Cole, where are you?
Come. Join the family.
Open it.
Kameron likes the flash,
but, uh, we prefer this, right?
This is a watch
for a man of action. [chuckles]
- Uh, read the back.
- [box thuds]
What does the inscription say?
It's a date.
It's the day he saved my life.
Five years ago,
he risked his life to save mine.
I offered him a job,
and he has since become family.
[guests clapping]
Thanks, Tibu.
[Tibu] Thank you. Thank you.
- To family.
- [guests] To family!
[cheering]
They're celebrating.
But don't worry.
The sale will be dead tonight.
Wasn't so bad, now, was it?
[chuckles]
It was a wonderful night.
Everything okay?
Yeah.
I just, uh, never imagined
I would ever sell the company.
Never wanted to.
Then why'd you do it?
I did it for Kameron.
KMG was, uh...
my dream, not his.
The shipping business
is, uh, not for him.
I wanted to give him the chance
to chase his own dreams.
He'll never forget it, Tibu.
Thank you.
Why are we going this way?
Looks like a road closure.
[policeman 1 speaks Thai]
[policeman 2 speaking Thai]
[in English] I'll back us
out of here.
[policeman 1 speaking Thai]
- [brake squeals]
- [policeman 2 speaking Thai]
[exclaims in Thai]
[in English] What is this?
[policeman 1 speaks Thai]
[policeman 2 speaking Thai]
[exclaims in Thai]
- [in English] Get down!
- [gunshots]
[yelps]
[hitman] Take 'em down!
[engine revving]
- [gunshots]
- [tires screech]
- [grunts]
- [car alarm wailing]
Ahh!
- [gunshots]
- [hitman] Shoot the tires!
- [car engine whirring]
- You okay?
I'm okay.
- [engine revving]
- [tires screeching]
- [gunman yelling in pain]
- Ah!
[Tibu breathing shakily]
- [Cole] Ah, shit.
- [distant police siren wailing]
[Tibu] What just happened?
[shakily] Those were police.
[shallow breathing]
- Please...
- [Cole sighs]
Please look after Kameron.
[labored breathing] Look at me.
If-- if I don't make it,
I can't help him.
Nothing will happen to Kameron.
- [gasping rapidly]
- Stay with me, Tibu.
Stay with me.
[continues gasping rapidly]
[gasping stops]
[emotional music]
[cell phone rings]
Yeah?
[Cole over phone]
Taran,
is Kameron with you?
[Taran] Yeah. I've got eyes
on him. He's just got back.
Listen, we were ambushed.
Tibu's dead.
The fuck?
Did you call the police?
The police are involved.
We can't trust anybody.
[zipper unzips]
One of these guys was American.
US passport.
-
6573247. Run it.
- [cell phone thuds]
3247.
Checking. Stand by.
I've got him. Jonathan Rogers.
Former marine. MARSOC.
Rogers is a crewman for the KMG.
He works for us.
He's departing
on the Artemis tonight.
It's gonna leave port
in two hours.
What's your plan?
[Cole] I'm headed to the port.
I'll find out who did this.
[indistinct chattering
on tablet]
Campallo is dead, sir.
Good.
So, what do you want?
We have a problem, sir.
His bodyguard got away.
Tell the police
to put out an APB.
But... one more thing.
Don't bring him in alive.
[reporter on TV]
Two police
officers were murdered tonight
while performing
a routine traffic stop.
Billionaire shipping tycoon
Manuel Tibu Campallo
-
was also killed.
- [gift wrapper rustles]
The suspect
is a British citizen
named Cole Reed.
Reed worked as
Campallo's personal bodyguard.
The suspect is very dangerous
and still on the loose.
A citywide order to shelter
is in place until--
[buzzing]
[continues buzzing]
- This is Ellis.
- [man over phone]
Miss Ellis,
we need you
to report immediately.
- Well, I, um--
-
The Artemis is short crew.
Departs at midnight.
We need you there now.
Sir, I just got in
from the Venus San Diego haul,
24 days across, and my flight,
well, it's in, uh,
my flight home's in three hours.
Miss Ellis, you're still
a probationary employee.
Sir, I-I have my daughter
this weekend in LA.
Listen, if you're not
at your post
on the Artemis in an hour,
KMG's gonna have to let you go.
[scoffs]
Okay. Roger that.
Fuck.
[exhales] Oh, fuck.
[Cole exhales sharply]
[keypad beeping]
[beeping continues]
[door opens, closes]
Kameron,
Detective Jamai is here.
- [Kameron] Evening, Detective.
- Good evening.
[Kameron] Evening, Officer.
My condolences.
Thank you.
I am sorry, but we are going
to have to ask you
a few questions.
- [sniffles] Of course. Ah...
- [phone buzzes]
[continues buzzing]
Uh, Taran, could you pour
these gentlemen
- a drink, please?
- Of course.
Hello? Who is this?
[over phone]
Kameron, it's Cole.
Listen.
Your father, uh...
[inhales]
I'm so sorry.
[sighs] I tried.
The police are here
asking questions.
On the news,
they're saying you killed him.
That's not what happened.
We were ambushed.
You need to stay locked down.
Whoever killed Tibu
will be coming for you next.
[exhales, sniffles]
[police siren wails in distance]
[phone thuds]
[port guard 1 speaking Thai]
[indistinct announcement
over PA]
[siren wails]
[speaking Thai over radio]
[port security speaking in Thai]
[tense music]
[port guard 2 speaking Thai]
[keyboard clacks]
[port guard 1 in English]
Make your way through security
on your right.
[port worker 1 speaks Thai]
[indistinct chatter]
[port worker 2 speaks Thai]
[device beeps]
[port worker 3 speaks Thai]
[port worker 2 speaks Thai]
[port worker talks indistinctly]
[crewman in English]
Hey, Jonathan!
[tense music continues]
[keypad beeping]
[news alert tune plays]
[reporter on TV]
For more
on this developing story,
we go live to Stan Beckwith
on the scene.
[Stan]
New details
are emerging tonight
following a shooting
in downtown Bangkok.
Sources say
the incident may have been
an attempted kidnapping
targeting KMG CEO
Manuel Tibu Campallo,
allegedly carried out
by his longtime bodyguard,
Cole Reed.
Campallo was pronounced dead
at the scene.
Captain. [knocks]
You may enter.
- Is everybody on board?
- Yes, sir. We're good.
Who are you, and what are you
doing on my bridge?
[Mateo] New third mate, Captain.
I don't need a third mate.
I have 20 good men on board.
Well, Captain,
I didn't wanna be here either,
but, uh, company asked me
to report.
Rama called in sick, sir.
KMG sent her.
[exhales sharply]
[smacks lips]
Would you like me to twirl, sir?
I'm not a fan of attitude.
Oh, no, neither am I. At all.
[paper rustles softly]
Well, if the company,
in all its genius,
wants you here,
then welcome on board.
[Angie] I like
your necklace, sir.
- You know what it is?
- I do.
That is a Viking symbol
of guidance and protection.
Impressive. Theo.
Can you take the young lady
to her cabin?
[Theo] Sir.
[Angie] Thank you.
You're welcome.
Anything else, sir?
[Marko sighs] The two of you
are on the night shift.
Keep an eye on her.
[tense music]
[horn blaring]
- Hard to starboard!
- [Theo] Hard to starboard.
Hard to starboard now.
[dramatic music]
[exhales]
- [knock on door]
- Yeah?
[Mateo] Captain has us
on night shift.
All right, I'll be there
in a sec.
[dramatic music continues]
[radio feedback squeals,
static crackles]
[muffled sobbing]
[muffled thudding]
[woman speaks indistinctly]
[lever handle creaking, thuds]
[metal groaning]
[faint thumping]
[thumping continues]
[metal groaning]
[woman speaks indistinctly]
[muffled thudding]
[metal groaning]
[suspenseful music]
[muffled sobbing]
[woman speaks indistinctly]
[muffled cry]
[flashlight clicks]
[Cole exhales sharply]
[clattering]
[clunks]
- [thud]
- [door squeaks]
[all gasp, whimper]
- [woman mumbles]
- [Cole] It's okay.
It's okay. I'm here to help.
How did you get here?
Does anyone speak English?
Doctor. Doctor.
Doctor.
You speak English?
[man coughs]
How long have you been in here?
Bangkok.
They say they let us out
as soon as leave port,
but they leave us in dark.
- Hot, dark.
- [Cole] Wait, wait.
Please. Sit down.
We need to be quiet.
[speaks Thai]
[Cole in English]
I'm gonna help you.
I'm gonna bring you water...
and food.
Some medical supplies.
[Seng breathes shakily]
[translating in Thai]
[Angie in English] Hello?
[Cole whispering]
You need to trust me.
I'm coming back. For everybody.
Okay?
[lever handle thuds]
[Angie] Hello?
[metal groaning]
Hello?
Is anybody down here?
- [thud]
- [door squeaking]
- [Angie] Oh, my God.
- [all gasp]
Oh, my God. [sniffles]
Okay. It's-it's-- it's okay.
C-come.
Come. One by one.
All right, just-just--
just stay in this area, okay?
We'll help you.
Okay. [breathes sharply]
- Mateo?
- [radio static crackles]
Fuck.
Oh, God.
Your daughter's injured.
Okay, is-is--
is anybody else injured?
[Seng speaks Thai]
[woman coughs]
[in English]
Uh, you with the man?
Uh, he get us food and water
a-and medicine for my daughter.
[Angie] What? W-what man? No.
Look, just... stay calm.
We're gonna help you, all right?
We're gonna get you food and
water. Just-- just stay calm.
Josef!
What's happening?
These people need water
and a medic, all right?
I'm gonna wake the captain.
Go help them.
- Come on, go!
- Yes, I'll-- I'll handle it.
[men whispering]
[knocking on door]
- [water splashes]
- [razor clangs]
[Angie continues knocking]
Captain. Captain!
- [water splashes]
- [razor clangs]
[Angie knocks] Captain?
Hold on.
[towel thumps]
- What is it?
- Captain,
we found
a few dozen people locked
in a container
in the lower hold.
What? Come on in. Come on in.
- They're not in good shape.
- What?
- What-- what's going on?
- They're dehydrated. They're--
[sighs]
Fuck, there's a little girl.
Jesus Christ.
Simon and Josef,
they're down there with them.
- That's good. That's very good.
- Yeah.
Now, calm down
and relax a little bit.
- I'm calm.
- Have a seat.
Captain to bridge.
[Mateo over radio]
Go ahead, sir.
Ellis found some people locked
in one of the lower
container holds.
She's here with me now.
Let's follow protocol.
Yes, sir.
[radio thuds]
- We should call the navy, sir.
- Yes, I will.
But let's find out
what's going on first.
I think it's pretty clear
what's going on, sir.
I hear you, and we got this.
I'm gonna get a hold
of the doctor
and you can guide him down,
okay?
-
Jones for Captain.
- Sit down and relax.
You did a good job.
Very good. Please sit down.
Sure.
Marko. Come in.
Do you need assistance, sir?
No. Ellis is with me.
And Mateo is-- is handling
protocol below.
Maintain your position, please.
Thank you.
Roger that, sir.
[Josef] Everyone, get back
in the container. Let's go.
[migrants speaking Thai]
[Josef in English]
All of you, move.
Get the fuck back inside.
Now!
[migrants yelping]
- I said, get back in.
- [Simon] Get back!
- [Josef] I said, get back in!
- [migrants screaming]
Get back in the container!
- Get back!
- [woman yelping]
[migrants continue screaming]
I said, get back in!
[Seng gasps]
[Josef grunting]
- You!
- [speaks Thai]
[grunting]
Aah! [yelling in pain]
[gunshots]
[grunts]
[grunts, whimpers]
[in English] Hey,
something's not right.
We need to call the navy.
- The captain just isn't--
- [gun cocks]
[Mateo] We're not calling
anybody.
[radio beeps]
Mateo to Captain.
Go for Captain.
Got her on the bridge.
I'm on my way.
[knife rasps]
- [yells]
- [both grunting]
- [Josef groans in pain]
[grunts]
[both grunting]
Step back.
- Sit the fuck down.
- Okay.
- [radio static crackles]
- [Angie grunts]
- [gun clatters]
- [both grunting]
[both grunting]
[Josef straining]
- Aah! [grunts]
- [Cole grunts]
[screaming in pain]
[yells, grunts in pain]
[migrants screaming]
[Dara speaks Thai]
[gunshots]
[Simon] Aah!
[in English] We need to get you
off of this ship
before the rest of them
get here.
We need to go up
to the lifeboats.
Stay close. Stay behind me.
Let's move.
[migrants conversing in Thai]
[tense music]
Fuck.
[beeps]
[signal beeping]
[Angie] Aah!
[Angie grunts]
Come on.
- Go fucking get her. Now.
- [crewman] Yes, sir.
- Move!
- [Mateo groaning]
What the fuck are you doing?
Get up!
What the fuck's wrong
with you, huh?
[Mateo]
It's still transmitting, sir.
[Marko] Then cancel it,
you idiot.
- [buttons click]
- Signal canceled, sir.
We're okay.
We're pretty fucking far
from okay.
Now, get your sorry ass down
and disable the lifeboats
so she can't get away.
Yes, sir.
And where the fuck is Jonathan?
I'm on it, sir. Jorge, come in.
[tense music continues]
Ah! Fuck.
Come on.
Hey, you.
You know how to use
one of these things?
Yes.
- Okay, listen.
- [Seng mumbles in Thai]
I'm gonna look
for the woman who found you.
I think she might be in trouble.
- Don't wait for me.
- Okay.
Captain on the bridge.
[Spencer] As you were.
- Good morning.
- Morning, sir.
Distress call came in
from a cargo ship.
KMG Artemis.
Nine degrees, 49 minutes north,
92 degrees, 56 minutes east.
05:33 hours local time.
That's the edge
of the Andaman Sea.
- What was the code?
- Attack, sir.
An attack? By who?
Last I checked,
we were 600 miles east
of any pirate activity.
They canceled the call
before we could respond.
Must have been
some kind of mistake.
[clicks tongue, inhales sharply]
Let's give 'em a call back,
Yates.
- Make sure everything's kosher.
- Yes, sir.
Artemis, Artemis, Artemis.
This is the USS Hazard Perry
on Channel 16.
[over radio]
Artemis, Artemis, Artemis.
This is the USS Hazard Perry
on Channel 16.
-
Artemis, Artemis, Artemis.
- Tsk.
[radio beeps]
Hazard Perry, this is Artemis.
Good morning.
This is Captain Spencer
of the USS Hazard Perry.
Who am I talking to?
This is Marko Madsen,
captain of the Artemis.
You must have gotten
our DSC call.
[Spencer over radio]
Yeah, we sure did.
So, what happened there?
I'm sorry, one of my guys
spotted light in our wake.
He had a run-in
with some Somalis
a few years ago.
You know how that goes.
Got a little trigger-happy
with the DSC.
But it turns out,
it was just a fishing vessel.
You're pretty far out for
a fishing vessel, aren't you?
Must-- must have been
a deep-sea trawler.
Not the first one we see.
Sorry to waste the navy's time.
Not at all.
Glad everyone's okay.
[radio thuds]
[Jamai] You have no idea
where he could be?
No clue, I'm afraid.
We have a call to you
from a burner phone,
shortly after the accident,
near the port.
Who called you?
I... don't recall.
To be honest, I--
I don't even remember
receiving the phone call.
There was a lot going on.
Okay, well,
please let us know
if you remember anything, or...
if any further information
comes to light.
As you can imagine,
your father's murder
is our highest priority.
Of course.
[tense music]
[indistinct murmuring]
[running footsteps]
[Angie grunts]
[Cole shushing]
[Cole] You're okay. Trust me.
[Angie gasps, breathing heavily]
[Cole] Open it.
[Angie grunts]
- [door closes]
- [lever handle clunks]
[Angie] Who the fuck are you?
I'm not one of them.
Right now,
that's all that matters.
[panting]
There are people in the hold,
and they're in danger.
They're not gonna kill them,
not when they're making money
off of them.
You don't know
what they're gonna do.
They shot me.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[woman speaks Thai]
[migrants conversing in Thai]
- [gunshot]
- [Dara] Aah!
[migrants screaming]
Check for more.
Everybody, let's go!
Out of the lifeboat!
[screaming continues]
[Angie] We need to help them.
[Cole] We will.
But first, we need to take care
of that wound.
Come. This way.
Down there.
[action music]
[exhales sharply]
[Diego hisses] Shit.
[tense music]
[groans]
Come on.
I found Jonathan's stuff
in a lifeboat.
Josef and Simon are dead.
- What?
- Yeah.
They were serious players,
Captain.
Whoever did this
had to be a professional.
It can't be Ellis.
She's fleet navy.
No combat experience.
And even if she did--
[Marko] Still,
she took you out, right?
Sweep the ship.
Find out who the fuck's came on.
Yes, Captain.
[keypad beeping]
We got a problem on the ship.
[loud whirring]
[grunts]
[Angie] Here.
[headsets beep]
[Angie breathing heavily]
[over headset] I've seen worse.
[Angie] I saw you on the news.
I know you're on the run.
Are you at least gonna tell me
your name?
Cole Reed.
[sighs] Okay, Cole Reed.
I'm Angie Ellis.
Okay, Angie Ellis.
This is gonna hurt.
Maybe you wanna talk,
take your mind off of it.
No. [exhales sharply]
Tell me something
about yourself.
[Angie breathes sharply]
Aah! Fuck me!
- You have a family?
- [breathes sharply]
I have a deadbeat ex,
and the most wonderful
little girl in the world.
What's her name?
[Angie] Violet.
Great name.
How old is she?
[Angie breathes sharply]
She just turned six.
[yells in pain]
- Fuck!
- Try to hold still.
[Angie] Oh!
[Angie grunting]
[relieved exhale]
Fuck, that hurts!
- Oh, fuck.
- [bullet clatters]
[relieved sigh]
Oh, my God. [exhales]
[Cole] Share custody
with Mr. Deadbeat Ex?
[Angie] No.
[inhales sharply]
Oh!
I used to share partial custody,
but then I lost it
when I got fired from the navy.
[breathes deeply]
I promised her I'd be back
more than two days a month,
and I--
I can't even fucking do that.
[sighs] There's still time.
- Okay.
- [grunts]
[breathes deeply]
I need backup
at the engine room.
- Oh. Yeah.
- [Cole] Okay?
- We need to keep moving.
- Okay, I got it.
Yeah. I got it. I'm good.
[loud whirring]
[over headset] She was here.
She couldn't have got far.
Move.
Any fishing boat this far out
would be registered
on AIS, right?
Yes, sir.
Let's check and see what traffic
was near the Artemis's position
- around the time of the call.
- Sir.
And, uh, see
what you can drum up
on this Captain Marko Madsen.
Hey, hey.
What happened in Bangkok?
On the news, they said
you're Campallo's bodyguard.
Did you kill him?
Did you kill those cops?
Why are you on the ship?
That is not what happened.
Right now, all that matters
is we get you
and those people to safety.
I sent out a distress signal.
I don't know if anyone got it.
There's no cell service
on the ship, but I know
that there are sat phones
and radios on the bridge.
Then that's where we need to go.
If we go to the bridge,
every man on the ship
will come running.
[sighs]
We need a diversion.
[tense music]
[Angie] In the last cargo hold.
This way.
It's here.
- [handle clanks, squeaks]
- [Angie grunts]
- [Angie] Ah.
- Here, let me help.
[handle clunks]
[doors squeaking]
[Cole] What about the refugees?
In an emergency,
every section of this boat
can be sealed off.
They'll be safe.
[ripping]
- [lighter closes]
- Let's go.
[tense music]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[fire crackling]
[alarm blaring]
Fire on five. Seal it off.
- Initiate fire protocol.
- [buttons click]
Listen up, everybody.
This is a diversion.
We have a stowaway.
I want two guards
at each tower door.
Diego, I want you to oversee
and patrol the towers.
- Yes, sir.
- [Marko] Mateo,
you go down with the fire team.
I'll surveil the deck.
Yes, sir.
[tense music continues]
[gun cocks]
[crewman]
A fire on the high seas.
That's definitely
the worst thing
you can have out here.
[fire roaring]
Increase pressure!
- [loud clang]
- [exhales]
[fire continues roaring]
- It's the batteries, sir.
- [Marko over radio]
Contain it.
I'm going up top.
[tense music continues]
[breathing heavily]
[loud clang]
[crewman 1 gasps, grunts]
[crewman 1] Aah!
[grunts in pain]
- [grunts]
- [bones snap]
- [body thuds]
- [radio static crackles]
[beeping]
Mayday, Mayday, Mayday.
This is the KMG Artemis.
Please respond.
All posts report.
Portside secure, sir.
[crewman 2 over radio]
Starboard
entrance is secure, sir.
This is the KMG Artemis.
Please respond.
[Mateo]
Fire contained, Captain.
Seal the hold. Return to deck.
[Angie] This is the KMG Artemis
on Channel 9.
Please respond.
This is the KMG Artemis
on Channel 16.
Please respond.
Captain to bridge. Report.
We're about to be short on time.
Captain to bridge.
Report.
- Shit.
- [beeps]
[tense music intensifies]
[exhales sharply]
They're on the bridge.
Diego, get up there.
[footsteps]
[Cole] Keep quiet.
[suspenseful music]
This is Captain Spencer
of the USS Hazard Perry.
[Diego exclaims, yells]
[Diego grunting]
[radio feedback squeals,
static crackles]
[Angie] Commander Spencer,
this is the KMG Artemis.
We need immediate
emergency assistance.
[Marko shouting indistinctly]
Who am I talking to
and who is "we"?
[over radio]
My name is Angie Ellis.
I'm the third mate
on the Artemis.
I'm with a man named Cole Reed.
We need help.
The captain is running
a human trafficking operation.
Our position
is latitude 45 degrees north,
- longitude 155 east.
- We need to move.
- Now.
- Send help! Fast!
[Yates] Was that gunfire, sir?
Get me that dossier. Now.
- Set course for the Artemis.
- Yes, sir.
[tense music]
[Angie] Come on.
We're going to my cabin.
We should be able
to get down from here.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[Cole] They're right outside.
[breathing shakily]
[Angie] If I-- If I don't...
Oh, God.
[Cole] Here, sit.
- Look at me.
- [continues breathing shakily]
I'm gonna get you back to her.
I promise.
Mm. Okay.
[tense music continues]
Bigger cut for each of us.
All right, listen up.
There is no stowaway.
That's Campallo's bodyguard.
[over radio]
So, there's a change of plans.
Going in two hours,
ship to ship.
- What's in two hours?
- I don't know.
- [Marko] Understood?
- [all] Yes, sir.
Move.
[phone buzzing]
Go ahead.
[Marko over phone]
What the fuck is Cole Reed
doing on my ship, huh?
How is he even alive?
I thought we took care of him
when we killed Tibu.
What the fuck's going on?
Look, the kill team fucked up.
Don't let him fuck up
the transaction.
He won't.
We moved up the delivery.
I've contacted Bertus.
He's two hours away.
Fine.
Just make sure that Cole Reed
doesn't get off that ship alive.
I will.
You're gonna owe me extra
for dealing with this thug.
Any updates on Kameron?
Are we still in business?
The sale has been halted.
It's business as usual.
What is it?
Who's Kameron?
Kameron's Tibu's son.
And you think he's involved?
I don't know.
But Marko's involved.
- And he's gonna pay.
- [crewman] Move.
Couldn't have got far.
It's time to go.
[tense music]
[Angie grunts]
[gunshots]
[wind whooshing]
[Cole]
Until the navy gets here,
those migrants aren't safe.
We need to get below deck.
There are lots of places
to hide 'em down there,
but you heard him,
they're all being guarded.
There's gotta be another way.
We could try
the ventilation shaft.
Sir, the dossier you requested.
Marko's been with KMG
for 13 years, captain for ten.
Danish national, Jaeger Corps.
Tours in Afghanistan, Iraq.
Investigated twice.
Allegations of looting
and smuggling.
They thought he killed one
of his teammates on a mission,
but the rest of the unit
wasn't talking.
- Nothing stuck.
- And his crew?
Half of them are either
ex-military or ex-mercenary.
Spanish MEO,
Irish AOW, GRU.
What about the man
that Angie said she was with,
uh, Cole Reed?
- Anything on him?
- Not on the company roster.
But wait till you see this.
[reporter on monitor]
The suspect is very dangerous
and still on the loose.
A citywide order to shelter
is in place
until he is apprehended.
A cop-killing fugitive.
You have gotta be kidding me.
Just what this shitshow
was missing.
Get me satellite footage
of that ship.
[Yates] Yes, sir.
[metal creaking]
[Angie grunts, strains]
[wind whooshing]
[Angie grunts]
[action music]
[Cole grunts]
[Spencer] Well, shit.
Tell me that's not an MP5.
Sir.
I hear there's a fugitive
on board.
We know if he's a friendly?
Friendly or not,
make sure your men
are good to go.
We launch
as soon as they're ready.
Sir.
[action music continues]
[strains]
[crewman] I think
I heard something over here.
- Over there!
- Cole, someone's coming.
- [metal creaking]
- [flashlight button clicks]
[tense music]
- [gunshots]
- [bullets ricocheting]
- [scraping]
- Shit! [grunting]
[panting]
[wind whooshing]
[metal creaking]
[Cole breathing heavily]
[metal creaks]
[breathing heavily]
[thuds lightly]
[clanging echoes]
[gunshots]
[scraping, creaking]
[muffled thud]
[metal groaning]
[cover clatters]
[Angie grunts]
Now, we're even.
[crewman over radio]
Captain, we shot the stowaway
through the vent shaft,
heard him drop.
Don't know if we hit him.
[Marko]
Block the hole.
Return to deck.
I'll take care
of this guy myself.
Copy.
[Angie exhales sharply] Fuck.
[glass crunches]
Oh.
I'd like to see you twirl now.
Sit down.
The four of you, with me.
- Everybody else, fan out.
- [crunches]
- You keep an eye on her.
- Yes, sir.
[Marko] Let's go.
[Spencer] How far are we?
[Turner] Forty-two miles, sir.
Time?
Seventy-five minutes, sir.
Launch the VBSS crew.
Yes, sir.
[action music]
[hatch opens]
[engine revving]
[action music continues]
[exhales sharply]
- [gunshot]
- [electricity crackling]
[alarm blaring]
[alarm continues blaring]
[suspenseful music]
[inhales]
[alarm blaring faintly]
[blaring intensifies]
- [squeaks]
- [lock clicks]
[exhales loudly]
He's trapped.
We'll deal with him later.
Captain to bridge.
- Lock off cargo hold three.
- [crewman over radio]
Sir.
- [metal groaning]
- [straining]
- [groaning continues]
[groaning continues]
[thud]
[clattering]
[clanging]
[grunts]
[thudding, clanging]
Got the intel package
on Cole Reed.
That'll be all.
[Underwood] Cole Reed,
born and raised in London.
Mom passed when he was seven.
Father was a cop.
Grandfather was a cop.
Finishes school,
goes right into the navy.
Royal Marines Commando.
Two tours in Afghanistan.
Comes home,
joins the London police.
Police Combat Cross for acts
of extraordinary heroism
while engaged
in personal combat
with an armed adversary.
Meritorious Police Duty Award
for an act
of extraordinary bravery
intelligently performed
in the line of duty.
Ends up serving under his dad
in the high-speed SCO19
Specialist Firearms Command.
His unit was stalking
a mob operation.
On the takedown night,
Reed went too far,
disobeyed orders,
got himself stuck inside.
His father went in to save him
and was shot and killed.
Wait a second.
His father was killed
saving him?
[Underwood] Yes, sir.
[Spencer] Jesus.
So, why'd he leave the UK?
[Underwood]
File goes cold.
A lot of people looking
for payback,
and, well...
he has no family left.
[Spencer breathes deeply]
I'll bet my pension
and my '67 Shelby
that whoever killed Campallo
is on that boat...
and Cole Reed is there
to square things up.
[tense music]
[singing in Thai]
[breathes heavily]
[breathes sharply]
[metal squeaks, creaking]
[gasps softly]
[ship horn blaring]
- [thudding]
- [sniffles]
[Marko] Lower the gangway.
- Lowering gangway.
- [button clicks]
[whirring]
[metal groaning]
[squeaks]
[phone ringtone playing]
Did the funds hit?
Funds confirmed.
What about our problem?
It's been contained.
Let's go and meet our guests.
[intriguing music]
Take them to the cargo.
- Ah, Cap.
- [Marko] Bertus.
[Bertus] Let's do it.
I saw smoke coming
from your ship on the way in.
Oh, yeah?
Well, what happens on my ship
is none of your business.
[Bertus chuckles]
- You wanna do this or what?
- Yeah.
Let's go inspect the goods.
I need to find myself
a clean one.
Best part of this job
is the ride home.
- Get in.
- [woman yelps]
Move.
[crewman] Get in there.
[thudding, clattering]
Thank you, Tibu.
[straining]
[sighs]
[metal creaking]
[action music]
[engine rumbling]
[grunting]
[light bulb buzzing]
[suspenseful music]
[ominous music]
[breathing sharply]
[grunting]
- Aah! [grunting]
- [strap creaking]
- [Cole grunts]
- [body thuds]
[intense music]
[Angie grunts]
[woman whimpering]
Here they are.
Now, get 'em off my ship.
- [crewmen grunt]
- [body thuds]
[gun cocks]
[Bertus]
What the fuck is going on?
[migrants gasp, whimper]
We have a stowaway.
A stowaway?
Yeah.
Well, what happens on your ship
is my fucking business now.
Calm down.
Everybody, calm down. Okay?
I will fix it. Calm down.
Boys, go down
and take care of this guy. Now.
Go! Go, go, go!
Mateo, go to the bridge
and deal with that bitch
once and for all.
- You understand?
- Yes, sir.
[clunks]
[door groaning]
[breathing sharply]
[door groans]
[gasps]
- [crewman grunting]
- [gunshots]
- [blood spurts]
- [body thuds]
[tense music]
[Angie grunts]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[crunches]
[crewman yelling,
grunts in pain]
- [crewman groans, grunts]
- [glass crackles]
[panting]
[running footsteps]
- [Mateo] Aah!
- [body thuds]
Fucker.
[breathing heavily]
[tense music continues]
[grunting]
Aah!
- [Cole grunting]
- [crewman 1 groans]
[grunts]
[crewman 2 grunting]
[body thuds]
[whispering] Shh.
Go to the stairs.
I'll go. Yeah?
[suspenseful music]
- [exhales sharply]
- [door creaks]
[grunting]
- [bones snap]
- [grunts]
[grunts]
[tense music]
[knife clatters]
- [gunshots]
- [panting]
[gun clicks]
[door groans]
[tense music intensifies]
[gunshots]
[gun clicks]
[both grunting]
[yells, grunts]
[Cole exhales sharply]
[both grunting, straining]
- [kick lands]
- [grunting]
- [both grunting]
- [Marko] Ah!
[Cole yells, grunting in pain]
- [Marko grunts]
- [Cole yells]
[Cole straining]
[grunts]
[foreboding music]
[Marko] Ahh! [grunts]
[metal groaning]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[grunting continues]
[yelling, grunting]
[Marko] Ahh!
[loud clanging]
[Marko grunts]
[straining]
- [grunts]
- [Marko yelling in pain]
- [Cole yells]
- [Marko grunts, groans]
[Cole grunts, coughs]
[breathing heavily, grunts]
[Marko grunts]
[growls]
You should have died in Bangkok.
- [hook pierces flesh]
- [Marko yells in pain]
[both grunting]
[Marko yells, grunts in pain]
- [Cole grunting]
- [Marko grunts, yells in pain]
Aah! [panting, grunting]
- [Marko growls] Aah!
- [grunts]
- [yelling in pain]
[Marko grunting in pain]
[grunts in pain]
[yelling in pain]
Ah!
This is for Tibu.
[spear gun thuds]
[sighs]
[dramatic music]
[bird squawking]
[bird continues squawking]
[dramatic music continues]
[Tully] Stay the fuck down.
Just stay down.
Don't you fucking move.
- Get the cuffs on him.
- [Navy Seal] Yes, sir.
[Angie] Wait!
[Navy Seal] Move it.
[running footsteps]
[Angie grunts]
[Angie] I'm not armed.
- Who are you?
- I'm Angie Ellis. I called you.
I'm the third mate.
He has nothing to do with this.
He saved us.
[Tully] Where's the rest
of the crew?
[Angie] They're dead.
[Tully] How many were there?
[Angie] About 20.
And the captain.
Is that Cole Reed?
No.
That's my shipmate.
You're telling us
that that isn't Cole?
Cole was shot.
He went overboard.
Ah.
- So that's how it went down?
- [inhales]
Yeah, that's how
it went down, sir.
[Tully] Keep an eye on her.
[exhales]
[Tully] Get him up.
Looks like you had a rough day.
Let's check you out.
There are people on that ship
that need medical attention.
- All right?
- Oh, yeah.
[Angie] Yes, that's correct.
I'll be waiting. Thank you.
They're sending me a crew
to help me
with the route back to LA.
[smacks lips]
So it's Captain Ellis now.
[laughs]
[Seng speaks Thai]
[Angie in English]
Yeah, I don't think so.
Is that Captain Marko's
sat phone?
It is.
Does it have a call log on it?
Of course.
- [Angie chuckles]
- Thank you.
Thank you.
[indistinct chatter]
[Angie]
So, where will you go now?
If you go back to Bangkok,
you know that they're gonna try
and kill you.
I need to finish this.
Get home to Violet.
[chuckles softly] I will.
[gasps softly] Ah.
[soft music]
[Spencer]
Is the Artemis secured?
[Tully]
Yes, sir.
Artemis secure.
[Spencer]
Is Cole Reed secured?
According to Miss Ellis,
Reed was killed in action, sir.
Marko and all 20
of his crew killed.
Twenty killed?
[Tully over sat phone]
Twenty-one, sir.
Plus the pirates.
There was one friendly crewman
we didn't identify
who appears to be taking off
on the pirate boat, sir.
[Spencer]
Wait a second.
Let me get this straight.
Cole Reed is KIA,
but you do not have a body,
and now, there's
this unidentified crewman
heading off on a pirate ship.
Do I have that correct?
[Tully]
Yes, sir, that's correct.
You want us to intercept?
Well, since he is not Cole Reed,
he is not our problem.
I would agree, sir.
[tense music]
[cell phone ringing]
[Cole over phone]
It's me.
Jesus. Where are you?
I need you to run a number.
One sec.
- [keyboard clacks]
- Go on.
667-213-4777.
[Taran] Jaran Daniles.
I'm coming back.
[sat phone beeps]
[tense music continues]
[woman] Such a lovely service.
I thought everyone did
such a beautiful job.
[man] The community
will miss him so much.
[foreboding music]
Get in.
[car door closes]
[Cole breathes deeply]
You don't understand.
I just let them use the ships
to transport cargo,
and they paid me.
They paid me a lot.
But I had no idea what they were
really asking me to do.
You have to believe me.
And then they stopped asking
and they started threatening.
And that's when things
got out of hand.
Multiple shipments every week.
Why didn't you come to me?
Because I thought
I had it handled.
I thought selling the company
would get me out.
But I never knew that they...
I didn't think
they'd go this far.
You got your father killed.
[sighs, inhales sharply]
And you're gonna have to live
with that.
For the rest of your life.
[inhales shakily]
[sighs] Take him home.
[car door opens]
[car door closes]
[intense music]
[loud crash]
[metal squeaking]
[engine hisses]
[car door closes]
[Daniles groaning]
[Daniles gasps]
[grunting, panting]
Why kill Tibu?
Tibu dies,
the company goes to Kameron,
who's compromised,
who we control,
and our cargo business goes on.
You mean the human beings
you were trafficking?
What do you want?
[continues panting]
Everybody wants something.
Tell me what you want.
I'll get it for you.
What the fuck do you want?
[Daniles grunts]
Vengeance.
[intense music]
[music fades out]
[tense music]
[unsettling music]
[music fades out]
[intriguing music]
[soft music]
[music fades out]
[dramatic music]